Guide to the Robert K. Merton Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Correspondence, 1930-2003
  - Subseries II.3: With Students, 1942-2001
    - General
      - Student Inquiries Regarding Writings, 1955-1986, (2 Folders) (Box 122, Folder 13-14)
    - A--General, 1946-1986 (Box 118, Folder 1)
    - Aidala, Angela, 1972-1979 (Box 118, Folder 2)
    - B--General, 1946-1986, (2 Folders) (Box 118, Folder 3-4)
    - C--General, 1947-1986, (2 Folders) (Box 118, Folder 5-6)
    - Caplovitz, David, 1943, 1959-1992, (2 Folders) (Box 118, Folder 7-8)
    - Cerebrog, Jefin, 1982-1983 (Box 118, Folder 9)
    - Cohen, Robert, 1981-1982 (Box 118, Folder 10)
    - Cournand, Marie-Claire, 1978 (Box 251, Folder 12)
    - Cozzens, Susan, 1977-1986 (Box 118, Folder 11)
    - Cullen, Frank, 1976 (Box 118, Folder 12)
    - Cushing, Brandon, 1977-1979 (Box 118, Folder 13)
    - D--General, 1943-1984 (Box 119, Folder 1)
    - Ditz, Toby, 1981-1982 (Box 119, Folder 2)
    - E--General, 1950-1986 (Box 119, Folder 3)
    - F--General, 1945-1988 (Box 119, Folder 4)
    - Friedman, Nathalie Schacter, 1968 (Box 251, Folder 13)
    - G--General, 1942-1981, (2 Folders) (Box 119, Folder 5-6)
    - Gieryn, Thomas,1976-1978 (Box 119, Folder 7)
    - Gutman, Robert, 1948-1954 (Box 119, Folder 8)
    - H--General, 1946-1987, (2 Folders) (Box 119, Folder 9-10)
    - Haritos, Rosa, 1983-1984 (Box 119, Folder 11)
    - Hoffman, Lily, 1980-1982 (Box 119, Folder 12)
    - I--General, 1949-1957, 1972 (Box 119, Folder 13)
    - J--General, 1944-1981 (Box 119, Folder 14)
    - K--General, 1947-1986, (2 Folders) (Box 120, Folder 1-2)
    - Koerber, William, 1976-1983 (Box 120, Folder 3)
    - L--General, 1948-1983 (Box 120, Folder 4)
    - Labov, Teresa, 1972-1986 (Box 120, Folder 5)
    - Lennon, Mary Clare, 1981 (Box 120, Folder 6)
    - Louis, Karen, 1981 (Box 120, Folder 7)
    - M--General, 1942-1988, (2 Folders) (Box 120, Folder 8-9)
    - Manacher, Horace, 1949-1951 (Box 120, Folder 10)
    - Marullo, Sam, 1981 (Box 120, Folder 11)
    - Messeri, Peter, 1975-1985 (Box 120, Folder 12)
    - Murphree, Mary, 1978-1982 (Box 120, Folder 13)
    - N--General, 1945-1983 (Box 120, Folder 14)
    - Nicholls, William, 1954-1977 (Box 120, Folder 15)
    - Nordmann, Alfred, 1982-1984 (Box 120, Folder 16)
    - O--General, 1947-1977 (Box 121, Folder 1)
    - P--General, 1947-1984 (Box 121, Folder 2)
    - Poling, Daniel, 1963-1965 (Box 121, Folder 3)
    - Price, Charlton, 1958-1964 (Box 121, Folder 4)
    - R--General, 1949-1983 (Box 121, Folder 5)
    - Rosen, Matthew, 1974-1981 (Box 121, Folder 6)
    - S--General, 1946-1982 (Box 121, Folder 7)
    - Schechter, Jay, 1978-1986 (Box 121, Folder 8)
    - Schott, Thomas, 1982-1985 (Box 121, Folder 9)
    - Shalin, Dmitri, 1976-1986 (Box 121, Folder 10)
    - Silver, Marc, 1981-1982 (Box 121, Folder 11)
    - Simmel, Arnold, 1965 (Box 150, Folder 11)
    - Stern, Lawrence, 1983-1984 (Box 121, Folder 12)
    - T--General, 1942-1972 (Box 121, Folder 13)
    - Thomas, Judith, 1979-1983 (Box 122, Folder 1)
    - U--General, 1970-1971 (Box 122, Folder 2)
    - V--General, 1963-1970 (Box 122, Folder 3)
    - Volinn, Ernest, 1982 (Box 122, Folder 4)
    - W--General, 1946-1980 (Box 122, Folder 5)
    - White, Marni, 1981 (Box 122, Folder 6)
    - X-Z--General, 1951-1988 (Box 122, Folder 7)
    - Smelser, Neil J., 1962-2000 (Restricted until 2013) (Box 363, Folder 19)
- Series III: Course Materials, 1928-1998
  Course materials document Robert K. Merton's academic pursuits, from his studies as an undergraduate student at Temple University, to his longtime Professorship with Columbia University's Sociology Department. In addition to providing an overview of Merton's teaching career, the records also trace Merton's early academic influences and activities. As an undergraduate at Temple University, Merton studied under George Simpson and later became his research assistant. While attending Harvard University, Merton was largely influenced by Pitirim Sorokin and Talcott Parsons. With Parson's encouragement, Merton undertook the role of both tutor and instructor with Harvard University's Sociology Department. Merton also found inspiration from E.F. Gay, who helped develop his interested in science and technology. This series underscores the significance of these early mentors and depicts Merton's subsequent scholastic activities, including teaching at various institutions and research endeavors. Series III is divided into four subseries that reflect the stages of Merton's academic career.
  - Subseries III.1: Courses Attended and Student Activities, 1928-1939
    Material in Subseries III.1 pertains to courses Merton attended as a student in the early 1930s at both Temple University and Harvard University. Items include handwritten lecture notes, course handouts, syllabi, examination questions, and a paper written by Merton. When known, course instructors are noted. Items related to course materials, but are unconfirmed as courses Merton attended, are included in the folder titled 'General.' This subseries illustrates the courses and professors that influenced Merton's early career pursuits and sociological interests. Of particular value is a document from a meeting of Parsons' Sociological Group. Merton formed this group with other sociology students while at Harvard University and they met frequently with professor Talcott Parsons to develop and discuss sociological problems and theoretical issues. Merton later cited the group and Parsons' role in his sociological development as fundamentally influential.
    - General, 1937-1938 (Box 123, Folder 1)
    - Anthropology Courses--General, 1929-1930 (Box 123, Folder 2)
    - Contemporary Sociological Theory with Pitirim Sorokin, 1931 (Box 123, Folder 3)
    - Criminology with E.W. Burgess, 1939 (Box 123, Folder 4)
    - Criminology and Penology with Negley Teeters, 1929 (Box 123, Folder 5)
    - Economic Statistics with Crum, 1932 (Box 123, Folder 6)
    - Economics with E.Gay, 1931-1932 (Box 123, Folder 7)
    - The Far East (Professor Unknown), 1930 (Box 123, Folder 8)
    - Modern Economics with O.H. Taylor, 1937-1938 (Box 123, Folder 9)
    - Parsons’ Sociological Group, 1937 (Box 148, Folder 2)
    - Principles of Sociology with George Simpson, 1928-1929 (Box 123, Folder 10)
    - Race Relations (Professor Unknown), undated (Box 123, Folder 11)
    - Rural Social Organization with Greene, 1932-1933 (Box 123, Folder 12)
    - Self Regulation of the Social Organism with Corrado Gini, 1936 (Box 124, Folder 1)
    - Social Dynamics with Pitirim Sorokin, 1931-1936 (Box 124, Folder 2)
    - Sociology I with Pitirim Sorokin, 1936-1937 (Box 124, Folder 3)
    - Student Paper--"Some Considerations on Durkheim's Sociology," 1932 (Box 124, Folder 4)
    - General, 1932, undated (Box 364, Folder 1)
    - Harvard University--Application and Graduate Student Dossier, 1931-1939 (Box 364, Folder 2)
    - High School Paper on Harry Houdini--Notes, circa 1920s (Box 364, Folder 3)
    - Student Paper--"A Study on the Functional Relationships Between Classicism, Romanticism and Various Social Phenomenon," circa 1930s (Box 364, Folder 4)
    - Tentative Projects--Notes, circa 1930s (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - Subseries III.2: Courses Taught at Columbia University, 1941-1987
    This subseries comprises the bulk of Series III and consists of items pertaining to Merton's lengthy teaching career at Columbia University. Courses taught by Merton are documented in great detail through extensive lecture notes (both preparatory and post-class), examinations, assignments, reading lists, syllabi, agendas and meeting minutes. Heavily represented in this subseries are seminars Merton co-taught with Harriet Zuckerman on the Sociology of Science. Related items include student research projects, proposals, and material relating to the referee process (also known as peer review). Subseries III.2 also contains information related to the University Seminars on the Professions, taught by Merton in the 1950s. These seminars led to the creation of the Casebook on Professions in American Society, which Merton co-authored with William J. Goode. The casebook outlines research and instruction methodology for the study of the professions and extensive documentation on its creation is included here. Items listed alphabetically by topic include assorted course lecture notes compiled thematically by Merton and research material that occasionally extends beyond Merton's teaching career.
    - General
      - Correspondence, 1950-1975 (Box 124, Folder 5)
      - Examination Questions, 1953-1970 (Box 124, Folder 6)
      - Lecture--History of Functional Analysis, 1971, undated (Box 349, Folder 8)
      - Reading Lists
        - General, 1942-1969 (Box 124, Folder 7)
        - By Topic, 1949-1957 (Box 124, Folder 8)
      - "Twenty Five Suggestions to Ladies and Gentleman who Have Completed an American College Education and are Now Pursuing Graduate Studies as Candidates for Higher Degrees," undated (Box 349, Folder 9)
      - Unidentified Material, undated (Box 124, Folder 9)
    - Analysis of Social Structures (Course #215-216, #G8015x-G8016y), 1947-1957 (Box 124, Folder 10)
    - Analysis of Social Structures (Course #215-216, #G8015x-G8016y), 1950-1954, (8 Folders) (Box 125, Folder 1-8)
    - Analysis of Social Structures (Course #215-216, #G8015x-G8016y), 1954-1957, (8 Folders) (Box 126, Folder 1-8)
    - Analysis of Social Structures (Course #215-216, #G8015x-G8016y), 1956-1963, (9 Folders) (Box 127, Folder 1-9)
    - Analysis of Social Structures (Course #215-216, #G8015x-G8016y), 1963-1976, (13 Folders) (Box 128, Folder 1-13)
    - Analysis of Social Structures (Course #215-216, #G8015x-G8016y), 1970-1979, (12 Folders) (Box 129, Folder 1-12)
    - History of Sociological Theory (Course #150, #G4050y),1945-1968, (12 Folders) (Box 130, Folder 1-12)
    - Lazarsfeld-Merton Seminar (Title Unknown), 1944-1945 (Box 130, Folder 13)
    - Selected Problems in the Relations Between Sociological Theory and Methods of Research co-taught with Paul Lazarsfeld (Course #319), 1957-1958, (2 Folders) (Box 130, Folder 14-15)
    - Selected Problems in the Theory of Organization (Course #321), 1955 (Box 130, Folder 16)
    - Selected Problems in the Theory of Organization (Course #321), 1955-1960, (6 Folders) (Box 131, Folder 1-6)
    - Social Organization of Housing Communities (Course #150), 1947 (Box 131, Folder 7)
    - Social Structure of the City (Course #138), 1941-1947, (2 Folders) (Box 131, Folder 8-9)
    - Social Structure Seminar (Course #331-332), 1948-1949, (3 Folders) (Box 131, Folder 10-12)
    - Social Structure Seminar (Course #331-332), 1949-1950, (3 Folders) (Box 132, Folder 1-3)
    - Social Theory Applied to Social Research (Course #213-214), 1943-1953 (Box 132, Folder 4)
    - Sociological Study of Medical Schools Seminar (Course #319), 1953-1954 (Box 132, Folder 5)
    - Sociology of Industry, circa 1946 (Box 132, Folder 6)
    - Sociology of Professions (Course #169), 1956-1958, (2 Folders) (Box 132, Folder 7-8)
    - Sociology of Science Seminar co-taught with Harriet Zuckerman (Course #G9531x-G9532y)
      - Bibliographies, undated, (2 Folders) (Box 132, Folder 9-10)
      - Book Reviewing (How to), 1972-1982 (Box 132, Folder 11)
      - Dictionary of Scientific Biography Project, 1965-1966 (Box 133, Folder 1)
      - Physical Review, 1966-1968 (Box 133, Folder 2)
      - Proposals to National Science Foundation, 1972 (Box 133, Folder 3)
      - Proposals to National Science Foundation, 1975-1977, (7 Folders) (Box 152, Folder 1-7)
      - Referee Process, 1968-1970 (Box 133, Folder 4)
      - Research and Reference Material, 1968-1982 (Box 133, Folder 5)
      - Requests
        - Graduate and Post-Graduate Study, 1966 (Box 133, Folder 6)
        - Research and Teaching Personnel, 1966 (Box 133, Folder 7)
        - Seminar Materials, 1966-1971 (Box 133, Folder 8)
      - Seminar Meetings, 1965-1966, (3 Folders) (Box 133, Folder 9-11)
      - Seminar Meetings, 1965-1976, (8 Folders) (Box 134, Folder 1-8)
      - Seminar Meetings, 1975-1985, (8 Folders) (Box 135, Folder 1-8)
      - Student Papers, 1965-1968, (11 Folders) (Box 136, Folder 1-11)
    - Studies in Social Structure (Course #195s-196s), 1942-1943 (Box 136, Folder 12)
    - University Seminar--The Professions in Modern Society (Course #417-418)
      - General, 1950-1952, (2 Folders) (Box 136, Folder 13-14)
      - Administrative, 1950-1951 (Box 137, Folder 1)
      - Bibliography, undated (Box 137, Folder 2)
      - Casebook on Professions in American Society
        - General, 1953-1957, (2 Folders) (Box 137, Folder 3-4)
        - Chapters--Research and Drafts
          - I. History of Professionalism, circa 1950s, (2 Folders) (Box 137, Folder 5-6)
          - II. Descriptive Statistics of Professions, circa 1950s (Box 137, Folder 7)
          - III. Public Images of Professions, circa 1950s (Box 137, Folder 8)
          - IV. Recruitment, circa 1950s (Box 138, Folder 1)
          - V. Education and Training, circa 1950s (Box 138, Folder 2)
          - VI. Career Patterns, circa 1950s, (2 Folders) (Box 138, Folder 3-4)
          - VII. Scope of Professional Activity and Inter-professional Relations, circa 1950s (Box 138, Folder 5)
          - VIII. Economics of Professions, circa 1950s (Box 138, Folder 6)
          - IX. Professional Role and Personality, circa 1950s (Box 138, Folder 7)
          - X. Professional Style of Life, circa 1950s (Box 138, Folder 8)
          - XI. Client Choice of Professional Services, circa 1950s (Box 138, Folder 9)
          - XII. Client-Professional Relationship, circa 1950s (Box 139, Folder 1)
          - XII. Client-Professional Relationship, 1952, (3 Folders) (Box 151, Folder 1-3)
          - XIII. Professional Associations, circa 1950s (Box 139, Folder 2)
          - XIV. Social Control: Ethics and Law, circa 1950s (Box 139, Folder 3)
          - XVI. Historical and Cross-Cultural Comparisons, circa 1950s (Box 139, Folder 4)
        - Correspondence, 1952-1959 (Box 139, Folder 5)
        - Grant Proposal, 1953-1957 (Box 139, Folder 6)
        - Readings, 1966, (3 Folders) (Box 151, Folder 4-6)
      - Correspondence, 1949-1953 (Box 139, Folder 7)
      - Cumulative Summary, 1950-1951 (Box 139, Folder 8)
      - Overview, undated, (3 Folders) (Box 151, Folder 7-9)
      - Preliminary Planning, 1949-1952 (Box 139, Folder 9)
      - Provisional Outline, 1951, (2 Folders) (Box 140, Folder 1-2)
      - Research Materials, undated (Box 140, Folder 3)
      - Seminar Meetings, 1950, (9 Folders) (Box 140, Folder 4-12)
      - Seminar Meetings, 1951, (11 Folders) (Box 141, Folder 1-11)
      - Seminar Meetings, 1951, (11 Folders) (Box 142, Folder 1-11)
    - University Seminar-- The State (Course #401-402), 1944-1946, (2 Folders) (Box 142, Folder 12-13)
    - By Course Name
      - Analysis of Social Structures (Soc #216), 1950-1956, (6 Folders) (Box 364, Folder 6 to 11)
      - Social Structure Seminar (Soc #331)--Minutes, Fall 1949-Spring 1950, (2 Folders) (Box 365, Folder 1 to 2)
    - By Topic
      - Institutionalized Evasions, 1952-1963 (Box 365, Folder 3)
      - Levels Analysis, 1943-1954, undated, (2 Folders) (Box 365, Folder 4 to 5)
      - Sociology of Reference Groups, 1950-1957 (Box 365, Folder 7)
    - General
      - Lecture Notes, 1946-1953 (Box 434, Folder 27)
      - Suggested Seminar--Social Cleavages, undated (Box 434, Folder 28)
    - By Course Name
      - Analysis of Social Structures (Course #215-216)
        - General, 1949-1972, (3 Folders) (Box 435, Folder 1 to 3)
        - Exams, 1966 (Box 435, Folder 4)
        - Lecture Notes, 1957-1971, (4 Folders) (Box 435, Folder 5 to 8)
        - Reading Lists, 1951-1974, (2 Folders) (Box 435, Folder 9 to 10)
        - Student Memoranda, 1963-1967 (Box 436, Folder 1)
      - History of Sociological Theory (Course #150)--Notes and Exams, 1950-1966 (Box 436, Folder 2)
      - Seminar in Social Structure (Course #331)--Minutes, 1949-1951, (2 Folders) (Box 436, Folder 3 to 4)
      - Seminar on the Sociology of Occupations (Course #331-332)--Notes, 1949-1951, (2 Folders) (Box 436, Folder 5 to 6)
      - Social Theory Applied to Social Research (Course #213-214)
        - General, 1949-1951 (Box 436, Folder 7)
        - Lecture Notes, 1950-1953 (Box 436, Folder 8)
        - Paradigm: Group Structure and Roethlisberger-Dickson Study, undated (Box 437, Folder 1)
        - Reading Lists, 1950-1951 (Box 437, Folder 2)
        - Student Papers, 1949-1950 (Box 437, Folder 3)
        - Theory of Social Control, 1949-1950 (Box 437, Folder 4)
      - Sociology of Professions (Course #169), 1956-1957 (Box 437, Folder 5)
      - University Seminar--The Professions in Modern Society (Course #417-418)--Casebook on Professions in American Society--Table of Contents, 1966 (Box 437, Folder 6)
    - By Topic
      - Continuities in Reference Group Theory--Notes and Research, 1949-1951, (2 Folders) (Box 437, Folder 7 to 8)
        (Includes Items on "The American Soldier)
      - Modes of Structural Interdependence, 1952-1964 (Box 437, Folder 9)
      - Social Myths of Science, 1958-1961, undated (Box 438, Folder 1)
      - Status Sets
        - General, 1955-1978, (4 Folders) (Box 438, Folder 2 to 5)
        - Activation of, 1961-1986 (Box 438, Folder 6)
        - Central Statuses, 1958-1971 (Box 438, Folder 7)
        - Conflict in and Articulation of, 1955-1976 (Box 438, Folder 8)
        - Cross Cutting
          - General, 1954-1975, (4 Folders) (Box 439, Folder 1 to 4)
          - History and Theory of, 1955-1971 (Box 439, Folder 5)
          - Versus Cross Pressures, 1947-1964 (Box 439, Folder 6)
        - Dominant, 1957-1975 (Box 439, Folder 7)
        - Key Statuses
          - General, 1958-1979, (2 Folders) (Box 439, Folder 8 to 9)
          - Central, Salient, Dominant, 1964-1977 (Box 440, Folder 1)
        - Role Sets
          - General, 1955-1987, (2 Folders) (Box 440, Folder 2 to 3)
          - Johnson, Allan Manuscript, undated (Box 440, Folder 4)
          - Types, 1975 (Box 440, Folder 5)
        - Salient Statuses, 1964-1975 (Box 440, Folder 6)
      - Structural Change, 1952-1968 (Box 441, Folder 1)
      - Structural Context, 1952-1966, (2 Folders) (Box 441, Folder 2 to 3)
      - Whyte, William--The Organization Man, 1958 (Box 441, Folder 4)
  - Subseries III.3: Courses Taught at Other Institutions, 1934-1998
    Subseries III.3 contains material on early courses taught by Merton outside of Columbia University, as a teaching assistant and instructor at Harvard University and Professor at Tulane University. Items also relate to courses Merton taught during summer sessions at University of California, Berkeley. Records include copies of course examinations, lecture notes, syllabi, and reading lists.
    - General
      - Syllabi and Reading Lists, 1937-1940 (Box 142, Folder 14)
    - Harvard University
      - General
        - Exams, circa 1930s (Box 142, Folder 15)
        - Reading List, 1937 (Box 142, Folder 16)
      - Correspondence, 1939 (Box 349, Folder 10)
      - Sociological Method (Course #5A)--Teaching Assistant, 1937-1938 (Box 143, Folder 1)
      - Sociology A (Assistant to Pitirim Sorokin), 1934-1937, (2 Folders) (Box 143, Folder 2-3)
      - Sociology 4, 1937-1939 (Box 143, Folder 4)
      - Sociology of Religion (Course #6B), 1938 (Box 143, Folder 5)
    - Tulane University
      - Administrative, undated (Box 143, Folder 6)
      - Social Psychology, 1940-1941 (Box 143, Folder 7)
    - University of California, Berkeley
      - Introduction to Sociology (Course #S2B), 1947 (Box 143, Folder 8)
      - Social Structure of the City (Course #S136), 1947, (3 Folders) (Box 143, Folder 9-11)
    - Harvard University--Sociology 4--Partial Classroom Notes, 1936-1939 (Box 365, Folder 6)
    - Rockefeller University--Correspondence, 1996-1998 (Box 365, Folder 8)
    - Harvard University
      - Sociology 4
        - General, circa 1938 (Box 441, Folder 5)
        - General Functions of Social Structure, 1938-1939 (Box 441, Folder 6)
        - Social and Cultural Structure, 1938-1939 (Box 441, Folder 7)
        - Social Structure and Social Planning, 1938 (Box 441, Folder 8)
  - Subseries III.4: Notes and Research, 1930-1990
    The bulk of this subseries consists of Merton's handwritten reading notes. These notes summarize writings by various authors and individuals on a wide range of topics, including sociological theory, philosophy, psychology, religion, science, and the law. The majority of notes are undated, but generally pertain to items written in the 1920s and 1930s. These notes were presumably composed during Merton's tenure as a student or in his early years of teaching, as reference for course work and lectures. This subseries also contains topical research files, including newspaper clippings, articles, and notes pertaining to various subjects. In many cases the topics contained in these subject files were explored by Merton in subsequent projects, studies, and courses. The records are arranged using the original order established by Merton and are organized alphabetically by individual or author's last name and by subject.
    - Individuals and Authors
      - A--General, undated (Box 144, Folder 1)
      - B--General, undated (Box 144, Folder 2)
      - C--General, undated (Box 144, Folder 3)
      - Castiglioni, Arturo, circa 1946 (Box 144, Folder 4)
      - Comte, Auguste, undated (Box 144, Folder 5)
      - Cooley, Charles Horton, undated (Box 144, Folder 6)
      - D--General, undated (Box 144, Folder 7)
      - Durkheim, Emile, 1953-1964, undated, (2 Folders) (Box 144, Folder 8-9)
      - Durkheim Emile and Freud, Sigmund, undated (Box 144, Folder 10)
      - E--General, undated (Box 144, Folder 11)
      - F--General, undated (Box 144, Folder 12)
      - G--General, undated (Box 144, Folder 13)
      - Granet, Marcel, undated (Box 144, Folder 14)
      - H--General, undated (Box 145, Folder 1)
      - Hobbes, Thomas, undated (Box 145, Folder 2)
      - J--General, undated (Box 145, Folder 3)
      - K--General, undated (Box 145, Folder 4)
      - L-M--General, undated (Box 145, Folder 5)
      - M--General, undated (Box 145, Folder 6)
      - Mannheim, Karl, undated (Box 145, Folder 7)
      - Marx, Karl, 1951-1963, undated, (3 Folders) (Box 145, Folder 8-10)
      - N--General, undated (Box 145, Folder 11)
      - Nisbet, Robert, undated (Box 145, Folder 12)
      - O--General, undated (Box 145, Folder 13)
      - P--General, undated (Box 145, Folder 14)
      - Pareto, Vilfredo, undated, (2 Folders) (Box 146, Folder 1-2)
      - R--General, undated (Box 146, Folder 3)
      - S--General, undated (Box 146, Folder 4)
      - Scheler, Max, undated (Box 146, Folder 5)
      - Simmel, Georg, 1957-1966, undated, (2 Folders) (Box 146, Folder 6-7)
      - Sombart, Werner, undated (Box 146, Folder 8)
      - Sorokin, Pitirim, undated (Box 146, Folder 9)
      - Spencer, Herbert, 1958-1963, undated (Box 146, Folder 10)
      - T-U--General, undated (Box 147, Folder 1)
      - Thomas, W.L., undated (Box 147, Folder 2)
      - V-W--General, undated (Box 147, Folder 3)
      - Weber, Max, undated (Box 147, Folder 4)
      - Z--General, undated (Box 147, Folder 5)
    - Subjects
      - General, undated (Box 147, Folder 6)
      - Freedom to Read, undated (Box 147, Folder 7)
      - French Sociology, undated (Box 147, Folder 8)
      - Human Relations in Industry, 1946-1947 (Box 147, Folder 9)
      - Jesuits, 1939, undated (Box 147, Folder 10)
      - Professions, undated (Box 147, Folder 11)
      - Propaganda, 1943, undated (Box 147, Folder 12)
      - Science Clippings, 1930-1940 (Box 147, Folder 13)
      - Social Change, 1961-1965, undated (Box 147, Folder 14)